I hope you enjoyed implementing the first part of
希望你成功实现了迷你项目的第一部分
the mini project which used a Monte Carlo algorithm to address the prediction problem.
即使用蒙特卡洛算法解决预测问题
In the dynamic programming case,
在动态规划设置中
our next step was to use the State value function to obtain an action value function.
下一步是使用状态值函数获得动作值函数
Remember, that we used this equation to convert the state values to the action values.
我们使用该方程将状态值转换成了动作值
And what do you think? Can we follow the same procedure here?
你认为在这里也可以采用相同的流程吗？
Unfortunately, no.
遗憾的是 不能
Remember that this underlined part of
该方程用下划线标注的部分
the equation encodes the one step dynamics of the environment.
表示环境的一步动态特性
This was known to the agent in the dynamic programming setting but in the
智能体在动态规划设定下知道这些信息
reinforcement learning setting the agent does not know these dynamics so,
但是在强化学习设置下并不知道这些动态特性
we cannot directly apply this equation as before.
因此我们不能像之前一样直接应用该方程
Instead, to get the action values,
为了获得动作值
we will just make a small modification to our prediction algorithm.
我们需要对预测算法进行小小的改动
For clarity, let's return to the simple example from the previous video.
为了进行阐述 我们再看看上个视频中的简单示例
As before, say the agent interacts with the environment
和之前一样 假设智能体在每个时间步
at each step choosing the action dictated by the policy.
都根据策略选择与环境互动的动作
These were the three episodes that resulted from that interaction.
这些是互动后产生的三个阶段
But now, towards getting the action values.
但是现在 为了获得动作值
Instead of looking at the visits to each state,
我们不再查看每个状态的经历
we'll look at the visits to each possible state-action pair then we'll compute
而是查看每个潜在状态动作对的经历
the return that followed from each state action pair and average them as before.
然后计算每个状态动作对之后的回报 并像之前一样取平均值
In this case, the action value corresponding to
在这种情况下 状态 X 和向上动作的
State X and action up is estimated to be one half.
动作估值为 1/2
And when we follow the same process to evaluate State Y and action down,
然后按照同一流程评估状态 Y 和向下动作
you'll notice that the pair appears more than once in each episode.
你将发现该状态动作对在每个阶段出现了多次
To address this, we'll need to again define some terminology.
为了解决这一问题 我们再次需要定义一些术语
We define every occurrence of
我们将某个阶段出现的每次状态动作对
the state action pair in an episode as a visit to that pair.
定义为该状态动作对的经历
And if a pair is visited more than once in
如果某个状态动作对在一个阶段中经历了多次
an episode we have our choice of either only taking into
在计算动作估值时
account the first-visit to the pair or using every-visit to
我们可以选择只考虑首次经历或考虑所有经历
calculate the action value estimate and you'll notice that each option returns
你将发现两种方式得出了不同的值
a different value where the first-visit method returns
首次经历方法的结果是 3/7
seven-thirds and the every-visit MC method returns
所有经历 MC 方法的结果是 2
two but if the agent gets more experience by collecting
但是当智能体通过多个阶段获得更多经验后
more episodes these values will converge to the same number.
这些值将收敛为同一数字
So for now, let's just assume that we implement the first-visit MC method.
暂时先假设我们实现了首次经历 MC 方法
Okay and it is almost as simple as that.
几乎就是这么简单
There's just one small problem that needs to be addressed.
但是还剩下一个小小的问题要解决
To see this, let's recall the policy that we are evaluating.
为此 我们来看看我们要评估的策略
It is a deterministic policy where the agent always selects action
它是一个确定性策略 智能体在状态 X 始终选择向上动作
up when in State X and action down when in State Y,
在状态 Y 始终选择向下动作
in particular, we'll never be able to estimate the action value corresponding
尤其是 我们将始终无法估算状态 X 和向下动作
to State X and action down or State Y and action up.
或状态 Y 和向上动作对应的动作值
This is because under this policy the agent will never pick action down when in
这是因为根据该策略 智能体在状态 X 将始终不会选择向下动作
State X and it will never choose action up when in State Y.
并且在状态 Y 将始终不会选择向上动作
Remember that our algorithm can only estimate
我们的算法只能估算
the action values corresponding to state-action pairs that it actually visits.
实际经历的状态动作对对应的动作值
So no matter how long the agent interacts with the environment,
因此无论智能体与环境互动多久
the action value function estimate will always be incomplete.
动作值函数估计结果将始终不完整
Thankfully, there is a quick solution to this problem that involves making sure that we
幸运的是 该问题有一个简单的解决方案
do not try to evaluate the action value function for a deterministic policy.
即确保不评估确定性策略的动作值函数
Instead, we'll only work with stochastic policies where from each state,
我们将使用随机性策略
each action has some non-zero probability of being visited.
在每个状态 都有一定的非零概率经历每个动作
For instance, if the agent encounters State X,
例如 如果智能体遇到状态 X
say it selects action up with 90 percent probability and otherwise,
假设选择向上动作的概率是 90% 否则选择向下动作
selects action down and if it encounters State Y,
如果遇到状态 Y
it chooses action down with 80 percent probability and otherwise, selects action up.
选择向下动作的概率是 80% 否则选择向上动作
For policies of this type,
对于这种策略
each state-action pair is eventually visited by the agent and furthermore,
每个状态动作对最终都会被智能体经历
in the limit as the number of episodes goes to
此外 如果阶段数量达到无穷次
infinity so does the number of visits to each state-action pair.
每个状态动作对的经历次数也会达到无穷
And that guarantees that we'll be able to
这样就保证我们能够
calculate a nice action value function estimate for
为每个状态动作对
each state-action pair as long as
计算一个完美的动作值函数
the agent interacts with the environment in enough episodes.
只要智能体与环境互动的阶段次数足够即可
You'll have the chance to test this out yourself soon.
你很快将有机会测试这一流程